Guide to the Stanford Alumni Association, "Origins of Modern Society," Videorecordings
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Alumni Association, "Origins of Modern Society," [videorecordings]
1988-1993
V0079
Stanford Alumni Association
3 Linear feet 32 videotapes (MII)
Lectures on the history, politics, arts, and philosophy of western culture by Stanford professors Gabriel A. Almond, William Chace, Gordon A. Craig, Terence Emmons, J. Martin Evans, Albert Guerard, Michael Jameson, David M. Kennedy, Carolyn Lougee, John Perry, Leonard G. Ratner, Antony Raubitschek, Lawrence Ryan, James Sheehan, Ezra Solomon, and Walter G. Vincenti.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Stanford Alumni Association, 1994.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
"Origins of Modern Society" was a course developed by Prof. Wayne S. Vucinich for Stanford University seniors. The video series was produced by the Stanford Alumni Association in conjunction with Stanford Instructional Television.
Description of the Collection
The "Origins of Modern Society" video series features lectures in Western culture by sixteen Stanford professors. The tapes were developed by Professor Wayne S. Vucinich and offered to Stanford University seniors as a capstone to their undergraduate education. The video series was produced by the Stanford Alumni Association in conjunction with Stanford Instructional Television.
Access Terms
Almond, Gabriel A. (Gabriel Abraham), 1911-2002; Chace, William M.; Craig, Gordon Alexander, 1913-2005; Emmons, Terence.; Evans, J. Martin (John Martin), 1935-2013.; Guérard, Albert J. (Albert Joseph), 1914-; Jameson, Michael.; Kennedy, David M.; Lougee, Carolyn.; Perry, John.; Ratner, Leonard G.; Raubitschek, A. E., (Antony Erich), 1912-1999; Ryan, Lawrence.; Sheehan, James J.; Solomon, Ezra.; Stanford Alumni Association; Vincenti, Walter G., (Walter Guido), 1917-; Civilization, Western.; Videorecordings.
Collection Contents
- Videorecordings
  - Origins of Modern Society #2: Dr. Sheehan (1 of 3), 1993 Apr 6; 1.1; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 1)
  - Origins of Modern Society #2: Dr. Kennedy (2 of 3), 1993 Apr 6; 1.2; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 1)
  - Origins of Modern Society #2: Q & A (3 of 3), 1993 Apr 6; 1.3; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 1)
  - Origins of Modern Society #4: Dr. Sheehan (1 of 3), 1993 Apr 20; 1.4; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 1)
  - Origins of Modern Society #4: Dr. Kennedy (2 of 3), 1993 Apr 20; 1.5; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 1)
  - Origins of Modern Society #4: Questions and Discussion (3 of 3), 1993 Apr 20; 1.6; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 1)
  - Origins of Modern Society #5: Dr. Sheehan (1 of 2), 1993 Apr 27; 1.7; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 1)
  - Origins of Modern Society #5: Dr. Kennedy (2 of 2), 1993 Apr 27; 1.8; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 1)
  - Origins of Modern Society #6: Dr. Sheehan/Q & A (1 of 2), 1993 May 4; 1.9; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 1)
  - Origins of Modern Society #6: Dr. Kennedy/Q & A (2 of 2), 1993 May 4; 1.10; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 1)
  - Origins of Modern Society #7: Dr. Sheehan/Q & A (1 of 2), 1993 May 11; 1.11; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 1)
  - Origins of Modern Society #7: Dr. Kennedy/Q & A (2 of 2), 1993 May 11; 1.12; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 1)
  - Origins of Modern Society #9: Dr. Sheehan/Q & A (1 of 2), 1993 May 25; 1.13; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 1)
  - Origins of Modern Society #9: Dr. Kennedy/Q & A (2 of 2), 1993 May 25; 1.14; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 1)
  - Origins of Modern Society: Interviews - Professor Sheehan and Professor Kennedy (Master 1 of 2), 1993 Jun 10; 1.15; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 1)
  - Origins of Modern Society: Interviews - Professor Sheehan and Professor Kennedy (Master 2 of 2), 1993 Jun 10; 1.16; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 1)
  - History 199: Gabriel A. Almond: "The Origin of Modern Politics", 1988 Feb 16; 2.1; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 2)
  - History 199: William Chace: "The Experimental Novel in the Modern World", 1988 Feb 23; 2.2; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 2)
  - History 199: Gordon A. Craig: "The Nineteenth Century: The Triumph and Crisis of Liberalism", 1988 Feb 18; 2.3; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 2)
  - History 199: Terence Emmons: "Russia and Europe", 1988 Feb 25; 2.4; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 2)
  - History 199: J. Martin Evans: "The European View of America", 1988 Mar 4; 2.5; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 2)
  - History 199: Michael Jameson: "Greece: The Invention of Politics", 1988 Jan 5; 2.6; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 2)
  - History 199: David M. Kennedy: "The American View of Europe", 1988 Mar 3; 2.7; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 2)
  - History 199: Carolyn Lougee: "The Age of Reason and Enlightenment", 1988 Jan 28; 2.8; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 2)
  - History 199: John Perry: "Descartes, Berkeley, Locke, and the New Way of Ideas", 1988 Jan 26; 2.9; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 2)
  - History 199: Leaonard G. Ratner: "Music as a Mirror to Society", 1988 Feb 2; 2.10; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 2)
  - History 199: Lawrence Ryan: "The Renaissance and the Discovery of the Modern World", 1988 Jan 14; 2.11; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 2)
  - History 199: James Sheehan: "The French Revolution", 1988 Feb 10; 2.12; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 2)
  - History 199: Ezra Solomon: "Economics as History", 1988 Feb 9; 2.13; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 2)
  - History 199: Walter G. Vincenti: "Thomas Edison and the Nature of Modern Technology", 1988 Feb 17; 2.14; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 2)
  - History 199: Albert J. Guerard: "The Novel as Art and Insight", 1988 Feb 24; 2.15; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 2)
  - History 199: Anthony Raubitschek: "The Legacy of Rome", 1988 Jan 7; 2.16; 1 videotape(s) (MII) (Box 2)